<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erik&#39;s Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://blog.baens.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erik&#39;s Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.baens.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-step: Kotlin and Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.baens.net/posts/step-by-step-kotlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.baens.net/posts/step-by-step-kotlin/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series of blog posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted todo. Read about them here.
For this step-by-step guide let&amp;rsquo;s do something basic and get kotlin compiling and running inside a docker container.
The companion repository is here.
Step 0: Prerequisites I am going to assume you have the following installed and already running. We will be using the local gradle wrapper instance after the initial setup, but you do need it for the initial creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Series: The step-by-step way tutorial</title>
      <link>https://blog.baens.net/posts/step-by-step-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.baens.net/posts/step-by-step-series/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of my development career, I&amp;rsquo;ve always tend to enjoy tutorials or explanations that guide you through concepts or frameworks step by step. Ones that have a goal and slowly work through things step by step, building upon itself to reach the final destination. All while explaining why this piece fits there or pros and cons of this piece over here.
These trainings are usually harder to come by because everyone is looking for a quick fix, or tool that does it for you automagically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to a HTTP server via Telnet</title>
      <link>https://blog.baens.net/posts/http-with-telnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.baens.net/posts/http-with-telnet/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to talk to a HTTP server via Telnet? As web developers, either front end or backend, we should strive to at least strive to have a understanding of the technologies we build our success on. And I&amp;rsquo;ve found through out the years that a surprising number of web developers don&amp;rsquo;t know how it works. So I thought it was fitting to start by looking at the basics of the communication mechanism we build upon and use every day, HTTP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>